Hello English learners. Welcome back to English Pod. My name is Marco and I'm Erica and
today we're bringing you again. The great series. I'm sorry. I love you part six. The
newest installment in the English Pod soap opera, drama, romance, love tragedy, all of
it here at English Pod and and in our series. So today we have a really great dialogue.
I just can't believe what's happening
here. But before we get into it, we need to
preview one word. That's right. So let's
take a look at it in vocabulary preview.
Very cablery preview.
Well, we're going
to preview this word.
Sleeping with. Sleeping with
someone. Sleeping with him. Yes.
So it seems pretty easy. I mean,
sleeping with, it just sounds like you are
in bed with somebody. Yeah. But you
are doing a little bit more than sleeping.
All right. So in English, this phrase actually
means that you are involved with someone and have an
intimate sexual relationship, right? Yes. You are in
a relationship with someone and you are having sex.
Exactly. So be careful how you use it because I know that sometimes you want to translate and just say, well, they are in
the same bed together, but it's not that they're having sex. Right. So most of the time in English, the phrase sleeping with
means that's right. Okay. Sleeping with. Be careful. Okay. Well, let's find out why are we talking about sleeping with?
Well, obviously somebody is sleeping with somebody. So let's listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and talk about.
This is ridiculous. I can't believe
you've been sleeping with someone else.
How could you do this? You
know what? I'm out of here.
Wait.
Doctor, how is this possible?
I haven't cheated on my boyfriend.
I have something to confess.
I'm sorry, Veronica. I lied.
Wait. What? What do you mean? I lied. You aren't
even pregnant. There's no body in the oven.
I was just so overwhelmed with jealousy that
I couldn't help myself. Veronica, I love you.
What are you talking about? Who are you? It's me.
Daniel, don't you remember me from high school? I sat
behind you in science class. I used to go to every
football game and watch you in the cheerleading squad.
You're insane. We never even
spoke. Why did you lie like that
to my boyfriend? Because,
Veronica, it's not fair. I love you.
I have since the first day we
met. Everything was going fine.
Until that jerk came into the
picture and ruined everything.
I went to med school and became a
doctor for you. You always said, "Are
you wanted to marry a doctor?" You
will be mine now. One way or another.
I heard everything you lying bastard.
Get your hands off of her.
Scandal again. Oh, this poor
Veronica and Steven, I don't
know how their relationship
could get more complicated.
It's amazing. They're having an
amazing adventure in their love life.
I'm sure glad my love
life looks nothing like this.
Alright, so we saw
some really great words.
So let's take a look at
them in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. The words
we're looking at now are about feelings.
So let's take a look at the first one.
Confess. Confess. To confess. To confess.
So confess. What does that
mean? When you confess
something, you tell a secret
that you've been hiding.
Okay, so that's pretty easy.
So you have a secret and
you want to tell it to
someone so you are confessing.
But it's usually something
negative. So Marco, I confess
that I stole five dollars from
you. Oh, you did. Yeah, sorry.
I wonder my wallet was lighter.
Yeah. Alright, so confess. I shall not
forgive you for this. Oh no. Alright,
let's take a look at our next word.
Overwhelmed. Overwhelmed.
I am overwhelmed.
So when I am overwhelmed, I am
filled with emotion. Okay, with emotion.
It can be good emotions and
bad emotions, right? Yeah, but you
just you feel too much. It's like
you're you're going to explode.
Okay, I am overwhelmed with joy.
Yes, or I'm overwhelmed with work.
And I am overwhelmed with
jealousy. Like this guy, right?
And that's our
third word. jealousy.
So this is interesting
because jealousy is the noun.
That's right. It's the
feeling of being jealous,
which is the adjective,
which is the adjective.
So what does it mean when you are jealous? It means
that you, you see somebody and you want what they
have. Okay, you want what they have. Yeah, so in this
case, the doctor is jealous of Veronica's boyfriend.
Because the doctor wants Veronica. Okay, jealous. So,
so Erica, are you a jealous wife? I don't know maybe
a little bit, a little bit, but I've never gone to
the extent of telling someone that they're pregnant.
Alright, jealousy. Okay.
And let's take a look at our
next two words, which are
actually kind of insults, right?
Yeah, they're not very kind
words at all. Okay, but you got to
learn them anyways. Yeah.
Okay, let's take a look at this one.
Jerk. Jerk. He's a
jerk. J-E-R-K. Jerk. Jerk.
So what does it mean if someone
is a jerk? A stupid and mean person.
It's plain as simple as that. Yeah, stupid
and mean. So, can a woman be a jerk?
It's mostly male, but now it's becoming
more common to use with women as well.
Okay, so I can say he is a jerk
or she is a jerk. Yeah, but it is
more common for men. Okay, and
now let's take a look at a last word.
You lying bastard. Bastard. Bastard.
Bastard. Wow, this is pretty strong as well.
Yeah, you got to be careful about
this one. This one is almost a swear word.
Almost, like on the line. Yeah. So what
does it mean if you call someone a bastard?
Well, literally it means your mother and
father were not married when you were born.
When you were born, exactly.
So it is a pretty big insult.
Yes. A little bit, I guess.
But it doesn't really, really
mean that your mother and father
weren't married. Right, but
it means that you are a jerk.
You're a jerk. You're a really big jerk.
You're a mean person, a really mean person.
So jerk isn't as strong as a bastard.
Yes, bastard is stronger. Okay, so you
got to be careful when you throw that
word in there or how you would use it.
And again, it's for men, right? Not for women.
Yeah, you can't use this word with women.
Okay, that's another one out there, but that
will have to wait for another English pod.
Well, apparently all of these words
are just for men. What did we do wrong?
Marco, I can't begin to tell you. Okay,
so let's listen to our dialogue again,
and then we'll come back
and look at some great phrases.
This is ridiculous. I can't believe
you've been sleeping with someone else.
How could you do this? You
know what? I'm out of here.
Wait.
Doctor, how is this possible?
I haven't cheated on my boyfriend.
I have something to confess.
I'm sorry, Veronica. I lied.
Wait, what? What
do you mean? I lied.
You aren't even pregnant.
There's no bud in the oven.
I was just so overwhelmed
with jealousy that
I couldn't help myself.
Veronica, I love you.
What are you talking about?
Who? Who are you? It's me, Daniel.
Don't you remember me from high
school? I sat behind you in science class.
I used to go to every football game
and watch you in the cheerleading squad.
You're insane. We never even spoke.
Why did you lie like that to my boyfriend?
Because, Veronica, it's not fair. I love
you. I have since the first day we met.
Everything was going
fine. Until that jerk
came into the picture
and ruined everything.
I went to med school and
became a doctor for you.
You always said, "Are you
wanted to marry a doctor?"
You will be mine now. One way or another.
I heard everything you lying bastard.
Get your hands off of her.
All right, so great stuff. Jerk bastards,
all that good words going around.
But we've also got some amazing phrases.
So why don't we take a look at those
now in Fluency Builder? Fluency Builder.
All right, so in Fluency Builder
today, we have three great phrases.
Let's take a look at the
first one, "Bun in the oven.
" A bun in the oven.
A bun in the oven.
Okay, this is obviously
an idiomatic phrase.
Well, it could be
literal as well, right?
Like, you could actually have
a piece of bread in your oven.
Right, bun is a piece of bread in the oven,
but in this context, we're not using it.
No, it means your pregnant.
Your pregnant. So the baby is the bun.
Yeah, and the oven is your stomach. Right,
so you say she has a bun in the oven.
Yes, she's pregnant. She's pregnant. Okay.
It could be difficult to understand if you
don't really have the explanation, right?
Yes, you would say, "What?" She has
bread in the oven. Yeah, a bun in the oven.
Okay, now let's take a
look at the second one.
Couldn't help myself.
I couldn't help myself.
So when you can't help
yourself, you can't control yourself.
Right, you did something,
but you couldn't control it.
You couldn't stop it. You couldn't stop it.
Okay, so let's listen to some
examples of how you would use.
I couldn't help myself
because it's a phrase
that you can use in
many different ways, right?
That's right. Let's listen.
Example one.
I just couldn't help myself.
When I saw your card, I just had to buy it.
Example two.
I'm sorry, I couldn't help myself.
I just started laughing.
Example three. That cake was so good.
I couldn't help myself. I ate at all.
All right, perfect.
Couldn't help myself. Easy.
Now, the doctor, he couldn't help himself
from lying to Veronica because he was angry
that her boyfriend Stephen
came into the picture.
Came into the picture
to come into the picture.
Okay, so what does it mean when
somebody comes into the picture?
Well, basically, you appear in somebody's
life. You come into somebody's life.
So imagine that your life is a picture
and somebody all of a sudden comes into it.
So they come into the picture.
They come into your life.
Come into your life. Yes.
So he's angry that Stephen
appeared into Veronica's
life and they're in
love and all that stuff.
All right, well, these
are some great phrases.
And why don't we listen
to them again in contact.
So let's listen to the dialogue.
This is ridiculous.
I can't believe you've been
sleeping with someone else.
How could you do this?
You know what? I'm out of here.
Wait.
Doctor, how is this possible?
I haven't cheated on my boyfriend.
I have something to confess.
I'm sorry, Veronica.
I lied.
Wait, what? What do you mean?
I lied. You aren't even pregnant.
There's no body in the oven.
I was just so overwhelmed with
jealousy that I couldn't help myself.
Veronica, I love you.
What are you talking about? Who are you?
It's me, Daniel.
Don't you remember me from high school?
I sat behind you in science class.
I used to go to every football game
and watch you in a cheerleading squad.
You're insane. We never even spoke.
Why did you lie like that to my boyfriend?
Because Veronica, it's not fair.
I love you.
I have since the first day we met.
Everything was going fine.
Until that jerk came into the
picture and ruined everything.
I went to med school and
became a doctor for you.
You always said, "Are you
wanted to marry a doctor?
" You will be mine now.
One way or another.
I heard everything you lying bastard.
Get your hands off of her.
Okay, so Veronica's not pregnant.
That was a close one.
Yeah.
Pure.
Actually, they're not married.
So this is a very
controversial topic, right?
Yeah.
Being knocked up.
Yes, nice phrase.
Nice phrase.
So there's a lot of interesting phrases
and ways you can talk about pregnancy.
So if you're knocked up, you're a pregnant.
Right. So you could hear that in movies.
It's not really, I would say,
a proper way of saying that.
No, it's not that polite because it
gives you the idea that it was a mistake.
Right.
So you would say,
"She got knocked up.
" Yes.
Another common
phrase is, "Preggers.
" Preggers. I heard this is
a more Australian, right?
She's pregnant.
So she's pregnant.
So it's actually a
pretty interesting topic.
I know that, for example, in Latin America,
if a girl that's maybe in her early 20s
gets pregnant accidentally by her boyfriend,
usually the families
expect them to get married.
Really?
Yeah, so it's kind of like,
should they get married?
Should they not?
So there's a lot of pressure.
A lot of pressure.
But it's different in
other countries, right?
So I don't know.
For you guys, what's it like in
your country where you live?
Is there pressure on the guy
and the girl to get married?
I mean, should Stephen and
Veronica get married in this situation?
Or what about just living together?
Or as they say, living in sin, right?
Living in sin.
Living together, living in sin.
Is it okay to just live
together with your girlfriend?
Or should you get married before?
Mm-hmm.
This is a controversial topic, so
we'll have a lot of different opinions.
But it should be interesting.
Yes.
So visit our website and
tell us what you think.
EnglishPod.com.
All right, guys.
We'll see you there.